eng zahid ur rehman

COMPUTER SYSTEM ENGINEER

MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER
TECNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER
SOFTWARE TESTER
DATA ANALYST





+971561150021



zahidrehman507@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/zahid-ur-rehman-528055199/

CAREER SUMMARY

I am a result oriented, forward looking & committed engineer professional having **3 years** of relevant experience in Mobile **Application Development** with **Flutter & Android Native** Platform as well as a Technical Support Engineers. I am confident and capable of working for android & Flutter development by demonstrating strong

programing traits with excellent ability to multi task with different people at one time under difficult situation. Gifted with the ability's to bring out the best in others whiles creating a healthy and friendly work environment, thus enhancing operational efficiency, optimizing resources utilization & achieve target

EXPERTISE

- Android Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- Canva Online Tools
- MIT APP Inventor
- Freed Camp
- MS Office
- MS Project

JAVA

- Dart
- Dai
- C#
- (++
- (

CERTIFICATIONS

- ESDA 2019, UNDP 2016, HRAP-2019
- MYSQL Database development mastery
- Globally Responsible Engineering Virtual Experience Program.
- JPMorgan Chase Software Engineering Virtual Experience
- Data Analytics Consulting Virtual Internship
- Software Engineering Internship
- Cybersecurity Consulting virtual case Experience
- Artificial Intelligence virtual Experience Program

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

B.Sc Computer Engineering

BAHUDDIN ZAKRIA UNIVERSITY MULTAN, PAKISTAN

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

- Seven Koncept's Pvt Ltd
- Netware Solution Pvt Ltd
- Mega Mind Pvt Ltd

- January 2022 August 2022
- August 2021-january 2022
- August 2020-August 2021

CORE STRENGTH

- Experience with third-party libraries and REST APIs
- Understanding of the Agile development life-cycle
- Experience with automated testing and building
- Experience with Version Control System like Git and GitHub
- Proven experience in writing readable code, creating extensive documentation for existing code and refactoring previously written code
- Experience with optimizing applications for Material Design.
- MVVM/MVC Architecture , Design Patterns.
- Solid understanding of OOP.
- Ads integration with different ad networks
- State management Bloc, Provider.
- Working with updated coding standard jetpack android, Experience with Android SDK
- Experience working with Google Analytics, working with Tensorflow / ML-Models.
- Firebase Firestore

APPS ON GOOGLE PLAY STORE, GITHUB & APP STORE

- **EzziClean:** UAE best Laundry & Dry Cleaning Service.
- Yas Clinic: UAE Yas Clinic Online Doctors Appointments.
- Life Is great In The 908: A local magzine and marketing service USA.
- ATS: Jobs Service App For Translation Empire Company UK.
- Formelation App: Al based gyms App for Canada.
- Rental Empire: Best online car rental service UK.

APPS LINKS

- **EzziClean:** https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=app.miracle.eeziclean&hl=en
- Yas Clinic: https://github.com/ZahidUrRehman13/YasClinicAndroidApp
- LB 908: https://github.com/marslannasr7koncepts/LifeIsGreatInThe908
- ATS: https://github.com/ZahidUrRehman13/ATS
- Formeltaion: https://github.com/asaxena187/formelation
- Rental Empire: https://github.com/ZahidUrRehman13/Rental-Empire

FINAL YEAR PROJECT

One of the most efficient and Highly demanding Security system in the 21st Century, It has the capability to secure your Vehicle/Automobile strongly against thief/robbers. It has three in one security systems itself. There is no way to bypass this system by the robbers

PERSONAL DETAILS

Nationality: Pakistani
Date of Birth: April 1998
Marital Status: Married